Rhiannon: Mental health issues in
children are generally defined as
delays or disruptions in development,
related to age-appropriate thinking,
behaviours, social skills or
regulation of their emotions.
Leah: These problems are distressing
to children and disrupt their ability
to function well in the home, in
school or in other social interactions.
It can be difficult to understand mental
health issues in children because normal
childhood development is a process
that involves all kinds of changes.
Rhiannon: Mental health concerns
may also differ depending on a
child's age, as they may not been
able to explain how they feel, or
why they are behaving a certain way.
Leah: If a child or young person’s
behaviour is a cause for concern it
should not be ignored, but should be
addressed either by trying to talk
to them, or those that know them best
and getting the support of a doctor.
Rhiannon: Once the problem has
been identified it is easier
to try to find a solution.
Let’s hear from someone who
can tell us more about this.